A Guide to the Books That Made the Difference Project Collection, 1980-1986
Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University
Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University
Books That Made the Difference Project Collection, 1980-1986
Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University, Blacksburg, Va.
Ms1985-003
8 boxes; 5.0 cu. ft.
The Books That Made the Difference Project Collection consists of subject files, clippings, correspondence, manuscript drafts, and audio-visual materials. The project was conceived in l980 by Ann Heidbreder Eastman, formerly of Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University, and executed by Gordon A. Sabine, formerly a professor at this university, and his wife Patricia, who interviewed people across the country, asking what book made the greatest difference in their lives, and what was that difference. The responses were collected for a book, Books That Made the Difference: What People Told Us, published by Shoe String Press in 1983. The theme of "Books Make a Difference" has been, and still is, used by public libraries for public relations campaigns. Noteworthy aspects of the collection include the 1983 book and the 1985 abridged version published by the Book-of-the-Month Club, and the original cassette tapes used by the Sabines to record the interviews.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
The Books That Made the Difference Project Collection was donated to Special Collections in 1986.
Historical Information
In a project jointly sponsored by the Center for the Book in the Library of Congress and the College of Arts and Sciences of the Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University, or Virginia Tech, the Books That Made the Difference (BTMTD) Project sought to discover how important a role books played in shaping people's lives. The project was planned, administered, and promoted by Ann Heidbreder Eastman, Director of Public Affairs Programs, College of Arts and Sciences, at Virginia Tech, and executed by Gordon Sabine, a professor of journalism at Virginia Tech, and his wife Patricia, an assistant professor at Ohio State University. The Sabines traveled across the country from July 1980 to March 1981, interviewed approximately 1,400 Americans, and asked them two questions: What book made the greatest difference in your life, and what was that difference? They interviewed a panoply of people, from celebrities and authors to farmers and laborers, who named books from the Bible to Raggedy Ann. The answers were collected for a book published in 1983 by Shoe String Press, Books That Made the Difference: What People Told Us. In addition, the Books Make a Difference (BMAD) idea was promoted nationally with, for example, Gordon Sabine's interview on National Public Radio's "All Things Considered" in which listeners were asked to write NPR about significant books in their lives, and as the theme of national library ceremonies, such as the American Book Awards. The concept was also used on a local scale, from promotional ideas for libraries given in the back of the book. In 1985 the Book-of-the-Month Club published an abridged version of the book.
Scope and Content
The collection consists of Administration and Promotion subject files, Center for the Book material, magazine and newspaper clippings, correspondence, manuscript drafts, Book-of-the-Month Club material, and audio-visual material.
The Administration and Promotion subject files are arranged in rough chronological order. The Public Relations survey involved a form sent to public librarians asking about effective ways to promote read ing. The Spokane Public Library material includes ideas to promote adult literacy and information on their efforts to boost reading through the use of television. The Dana Library Public Relations Awards contest and the Library Awareness Idea Search were entered by Eastman with the BMAD concept. The BTMTD Kit, which is included with this material, never proved successful. Poster Sessions refers to the use of a BMAD exhibit at the 1982 American Library Association meeting. PM Magazine material includes information on the possibility of a BTMTD spot on the show. Susan Neuman material relates to this professor's research at Eastern Connecticut State University of children's reading habits and Neuman's inquiries to Eastman for duplicates of the recorded interviews. The Sabines' Houston presentation was made at Westfield High School in the Spring Independent School District, October 2-3, l984. The Sabines' conclusions focus on their summation about the difference books make to different people. Reader's Digest material consists of mostly manu script fragments of the book organized by Gordon Sabine for an article that was submitted to but never published by Reader's Digest. Miscellaneous administrative information consists mostly of memos, ALA and agent's information, notes, clippings, etc.
The Center for the Book material includes meeting reports of, and publicity for, the BTMTD project.
The clippings are primarily about the BTMTD project, with a few scattered throughout on other related topics.
The correspondence consists of copies of the initial letters Eastman sent to State Librarians about the project, requests for information and materials from librarians, letters of inquiry about the project to the Center for the Book, and Walter Matthau's 1980 letter to the Sabines about his most meaningful book. Also included in the correspondence are the letters written to NPR in response to their request for listeners' to write in what book made the difference in their lives.
The book manuscripts include a card file of notes for the book, as well as drafts and cut- up fragments of the book. Book copy refers to a xerox copy of the finished book. A first edition copy of the book, Books That Made the Difference: What People Told Us is also included in the manuscripts section.
The Book-of-the-Month Club material includes a copy of its 1985 version of the book (pages 1-128 of the original Shoe String Press edition), as well as miscellaneous project material pertaining to the Book- of-the-Month Club.
The Audio-Visual material includes photographs, contact sheets, and negatives of interviewees in the project. One photograph is of Gordon Sabine at a teletype machine for deaf library users at the Free Library of Philadelphia and another is of him interviewing a woman on the beach at Sanibel. The order of the contact sheets and negatives follows the Sabines' trail around the country. See Container List for complete listing. Of the four 8-track tapes, one is of Susan Stamberg's NPR interview with Gordon Sabine, the second of an interview with Robert Cromie of Chicago, Illinois, the third is entitled "Eastman MS w/excerpts from BTMTD speech", and the last is of "various interviews." The slides are of interviewees. The videotapes include two U-matic cassettes, one labeled "Mr. and Mrs. Gordon Sabine, BTMTD, Black and White, no Sound", and the other of the BMAD slides which has a list accompany ing it. Another videotape is from the April 1981 BTMTD presentation for the Center for the Book, and a fourth is marked "Contents unknown". The interview tapes include conversations with such noteworthy people as Daniel Boorstin, Woody Hayes, Clare Booth Luce, Dottie Lamm, William G. Milliken, Studs Terkel, Andy Rooney, Edgar Bergen, Sam Bass Warner, Tony Randall, Barbara Tuchman, and Susan Stamberg. The interviewees on Tape are listed in a separate cassette index, appended to the back of the container list.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged by type of material.
Contents List
- Administration and Promotion, 1980-1983, undated.
  - Project proposal, with draft, to the Center for the Book, April 1980. (Box-folder 1-1)
  - Sabines vitas and photographs. (Box-folder 1-2)
  - State Librarians contacted by Eastman for project, 1980-1981. (Box-folder 1-3)
  - Sabines' travel schedules, 1980-1981. (Box-folder 1-4)
  - Public Relations survey, 1980. (Box-folder 1-5)
  - Press releases, 1981. (Box-folder 1-6)
  - Spokane Public Library, 1981. (Box-folder 1-7)
  - Dana Library Public Relations Award Contest material, 1982. (Box-folder 1-8)
  - Library Awareness Idea Search with BTMTD Kit, 1982. (Box-folder 1-9)
  - Poster Sessions, 1982. (Box-folder 1-10)
  - PM Magazine, 1982. (Box-folder 1-11)
  - Promotion ideas, 1980-1982. (Box-folder 1-12)
  - Promotional materials. (Box-folder 1-13)
  - Council for Florida Libraries Book and Author Festival packet and promotional tour material, 1982. (Box-folder 1-14)
  - Library Administrators and Managers Association, Public Relations section BMAD program, 1983. (Box-folder 1-15)
  - Shoe String Press material, 1982-1983. (Box-folder 1-16)
  - Sabine promotion, 1982-1984. (Box-folder 1-17)
  - Susan Neuman project, 1983-1984. (Box-folder 1-18)
  - Broward Co., FL BMAD program, 1983-1984. (Box-folder 1-19)
  - Houston presentation, 1984. (Box-folder 1-20)
  - "Conclusions." (Box-folder 1-21)
  - Reader's Digest material, 1981, n.d. (Box-folder 1-22 to 1-23 (2 folders))
  - Miscellaneous administrative material. (Box-folder 1-24 to 1-26 (3 folders))
  - Library of Congress Budget Record, 1981. (Box-folder 1-27)
  - Central Midwestern Regional Educational Laboratory, Inc., 1982-1983. (Box-folder 1-28)
- Center for the Book, 1980-1983.
  - Meeting and interim reports and proposals, 1980-1983. (Box-folder 1-29)
  - Kit and correspondence, 1981. (Box-folder 1-30)
  - Publicity. (Box-folder 1-31)
- Clippings, 1980-1986, undated.
  - Clippings, 1980-1981. (Box-folder 1-32 to 1-33 (2 folders))
  - Clippings, 1982-1986, undated. (Box-folder 2-1 to 2-2 (2 folders))
  - Roanoke Times and World News article material, November 1981. (Box-folder 2-3)
- Correspondence, 1981-1984.
  - Eastman letters to State Librarians with responses, 1981. (Box-folder 2-4)
  - Requests for information and materials, 1980-1984. (Box-folder 2-5)
  - Letters of inquiry about the BMAD program to the Center for the Book, 1982. (Box-folder 2-6 to 2-7 (2 folders))
  - Walter Matthau letter to Sabines, November 1980. (Box-folder 2-8)
  - Gereral, 1980-1984. (Box-folder 2-9)
  - National Public Radio interview, 1981. (Box-folder 2-10)
  - List of states, respondents, books, and quality control form. (Box-folder 2-11)
  - Letters, A-Z and unsigned. (Box-folder 2-12 to 2-17 (6 folders))
- Manuscripts, 1980-1983, undated.
  - Card file. (Box-folder 2-18)
  - Fragments of early manuscrip drafts. (Box-folder 2-19 to 2-22 (4 folders))
  - What Americans Say: The Books that Made the Difference, 2 copies. (Box-folder 2-23 to 3-1 (2 folders))
  - First draft I, April 1981. (Box-folder 3-2)
  - Second mansuscript, version III with updated pages, April 8, 1981.
  - Draft? 1983 (Box-folder 3-4)
  - Draft with index. (Box-folder 4-1)
  - Book copy. (Box-folder 4-2)
  - Books That Made the Difference: What People Told Us. Hamden CT: The Shoe String Press, Inc., 1983. (Box-folder 4-3)
- Book-of-the-Month Club, 1985, undated.
  - Miscellaneous materials. (Box-folder 4-4)
  - Abridged edition of Books That Made the Difference: What People Told Us, 1985. (Box-folder 4-5)
- Audio-Visual Materials.
  - Photographs. (Box-folder 4-6)
    Contact Sheets and Negatives
    Ft. Myers; Sanibel Island; Stone Mountain (Atlanta, Georgia)
    Florida; New Jersey
    Atlanta, Georgia; Indian Reservation
    Grand Canyon
    Denver; San Francisco; Houston
    San Francisco (John Frantz, Ernie Gaines, Ferlenghetti); Concord, California
    Phoenix
    Idaho (mayor to wheat farmer)
    New York, New York; Philadelphia
    Wellesley, Massachusetts
  - Films. (Box-folder 4-7)
  - Audiotapes, slides. (Box 5)
- Cassette Tapes 1-28. (Box 5)
  - Tape 1
    Side A: St. Petersburg man; Emma Simpson, 81 year-old lady; 100-year-old lady; Manchild and the Promised Land; Helen Bradley; Island of the Blue Dolphins
    Side B: Edgar Bergen; Mr. Degruy; Master's student, encyclopedias; Cora Groff; Dan Runge; Sarah Cook; Harry Wharton, postal clerk; Joan Hopkins; Ringling Art Librarian; David Williams (blind); Frank Cucksey
  - Tape 2
    Side A: Aldrane Schuchmann; Bill Stonex; Kercher; Dauthtroy; Ann Marie Costa; Dan Bernstein; Bruce Sparks; Mark Goumas
    Side B: Morris; Blue; Steffan Mallory and Tonya; Lois Rice; Ken Stevenson
  - Tape 3
    Side A: Librarian from Georgia; Anne Russell; Mary Rheay; Colleen; Thomas Moore; Jack Kraus; Mary Warren; Alma Greene; Sybil Bain; Roxanna Austin
    Side B: Ella Yates, Hawaii; Army rules and regulations; John Harte; Christopher Kane; Dr. Ellwood Boddie; France Fritzen; Judy Albright; Casper Jordan
  - Tape 4
    Side A: Willis Johnson; Vincent Davis, Native Son; V.P. Rush Honda, comic books; about George Bernard Shaw (Shaw Society)
    Side B: About George Bernard Shaw (con't); Bonnie Miller; Weller; About Carol Burnett; Sue Stacy
  - Tape 5
    Side A: Ft. Sumter (then speeds up, cannot be understood on this recorder)
    "Family Business"
  - Tape 6
    Side A: Gordon Canterbury; South African, Cry the Beloved Country; Mark Grubham; Arthur Brown; Mr. Linstrom; Nancy White; Joy Culp, Spokane, WA
    Side B: Leon Skip Roland; Utah Phillips; Barbara Scott; more on Joy Culp; info on Joy Culp's driver Kathy; Ron Dubberly
  - Tape 7
    Side A: Mr. Stuntz, guide and ticket seller at Tom Edison's house, Dan Youman; Josephine Mannella; (static...); Elizabeth Bryan; James Letizia
    Side B: James Letizia (cont.); Linda Letizia; Anne Dennis, Jonathan Livingston Seagull; Dr. Marvin Odro; Bruce Hugh, Peter Marshall; (static...); Teacher in Canada; Mrs. Payne
  - Tape 8
    Side A: Joan and Malcolm Miller, High Ice
    Side B: Malcolm Miller (cont'd); Mary Poppins; Textbook; Cope Gall Jr., Grapes of Wrath; Mr. Nelson; Gary Morris; Boy Scout Handbook; Irv Brown, Cry the Beloved Country
  - Tape 9
    Side A: Mrs. Pond, Seattle, WA; Wainwright; Virgina Burnside; Ken Ragland; Don Zoller; Ben Moon Railroad, sailor; Fisherman from Norway
    Side B: blank
  - Tape 10
    Side A: blank
    Side B: Roy Beck; W. R. Henderson; Minton Moore; Mr. Meek; Luther Baker; David Perkins; Sterling and Elizabeth Hinman; Mr Beach; Mr. Dabney
  - Tape 11
    Side A: Mark Couchman, The Monkey Wrench Gang; Beth Stolzy; Jane Diaz; Rev. Ramsey; Jane Diaz (again); stewardess; Ed Byers; Seibel; Mary Anne Toliver: Mrs. DeReemer; Pauley
    Side B: Pauley (cont'd); Ellen Crowley; Shirley Wittler; Halliburton Books; Boorstin's History Books; Little Anna of Lapland; G. Henney's Books; Lawrence Webber, (children should be read to); real estate consultant; Edgar Rice Burrough's books
  - Tape 12
    Side A: Tarzan, Zane Grey Books; Henry Shearouse; Lee Ambrose, The Fountain Pen; college course called "Age of Johnson"; Glenn Holliday; Ellen Kessler, PASSAGES
    Side B: Dottie Lamm, Working It Out; Father Woodridge
  - Tape 13
    Side A: Bill Barrett, author of Lilies of the Field and The Left Hand of God; Howlet; John Gardner's Excellence; John Murdock; Owner of a gold mine, Jesse Peterson
    Side B: Das Kapital, Mary Kennelli; Jahn McCardy; John Frantz; Jade Snow Wong; black writer
  - Tape 14
    Side A: Autobiographies; Poet, The Literary San Francisco Coney Island of the Mind; Positive Thinking, guide in Barringer Vineyards; Betty Theriot, Book of Mormon; Books on child rearing, Peresia Jackson; Rrobert Yamada
    Side B: Mary Kraetzer; Asst. Librarian; Gunther Barth
  - Tape 15
    Side A: Ed McMillan; (Nobel)
    Side B: Mendlesohn; woman who works on The Examiner; Elwood Nestler
  - Tape 16
    Side A: Greg Rayner; Louie Welch; Librarian; Mike Benedict; Penrod
    Side B: Librarian; Boy Scout Handbook; Chester Rozell; Willia Carey Graves; D.D. Lewis
  - Tape 17
    Side A: The Late Great Planet Earth; Stanley Marcus; Doorman; Patricia Sabine
  - Tape 18
    Side A: Sylvia Batenhorst
    Side B: Sylvia Batenhorst; Green River Bar, Alice Wenner
  - Tape 19
    Side A: Gerhard Zuther; Alex Lazzarrino; Lonnie Tilley, books by Roy Rogers; Frank Hulac
    Side B: Joe Kimbrough; Fr. Alan Moss; Carol Chrislock; Gail See; Harold Kittleson
  - Tape 20
    Side A: Zygmont Choroszy, concentration camp survivor
    Side B: Zygmont Choroszy
  - Tape 21
    Side A: Steve Nisbet; Louise Pratt Calcott; Roland Robbins
    Side B: Roland Robbins
  - Tape 22
    Side A: Roland Robbins (talking about Thoreau)
    Side B: Robbins (cont'd); Edna Heidbreder; Jane Gorden at Alcott House
  - Tape 23
    Side A: Bert Perkins; Edgar Allen, Sherlock Holmes; Leonard Quintavalla, U.S.S. Constitution; Durgur Park Waitress; David McCord; General Gavin
    Side B: George Gloss; Fenn; Sam Bass Warner; Tonroy
  - Tape 24
    Side A: Tonroy, Vanity Fair; Florence Ladd; Writer in residence at Emerson College; Millions of Cats
    Side B: Woman from Peron's Argentina (Manti); Newman's idea of the University, The Second Spring; Jane Manthorne, The Little Matchgirl, The Man Without a Country; Danny Thiel; Anthony Buscetti
  - Tape 25
    Side A: Unidentified man; Clara Garcia; Alberto Barreto
    Side B: Alberto Barreto (cont'd); Maria Sanchez; Mayor Willian Musso; Steven Aschoff; Jim Moomaw; Bob Van Dyne
  - Tape 26
    Side A: Bob Van Dyne; Bea MacDdonald; Fred Crossland; Marie Davis; Mary Flournoy
    Side B: Mary Flournoy; Hagemayer; Bill Andrews; Debbie Andrews; Wes Pippert
  - Tape 27
    Side A: Ed Newman; Nina Keenan; Tom Keenan
    Side B: Tom Keenan (cont'd); James Fox (cop); Family business
  - Tape 28
    Side A: William G. Milliken (Governor of Michigan); Bob Cromie; Bill Veeck; Kerri Byrnes
    Side B: Clare Booth Luce; Paul Tibbets
- Cassette Tapes 29-55. (Box 6)
  - Tape 29
    Side A: Paul Tibbets; Dr. Mayberry Mayo; Paul Tibbets; War and Rememberance; Pat Bartlett
    Side B: About Richard Burton; Bobbie Estrada; Jeanne Hart
  - Tape 30
    Side A: Woman in Indian Community; Bundy; Paul Beach; Pat Walker; Stacy; Fellow Graduate from University of Wisconsin
    Side B: Marcus Cohn; Minnie Pearl; Ann Eastman
  - Tape 31
    Side A: John Gardner
    Side B: Electronic reader for the Blind
  - Tape 32
    Side A: Blank except for a small clip from a broadcast, Daniel Boorstin
  - Tape 33
    Side A: Ruth Boorstin
    Side B: Susan Stamberg
  - Tape 34
    Side A: Dan Fader, English Professor from Baltimore
    Side B: Dan Fader (cont'd); Prof. John Forsythe; Mechanical Engineer; Phil Samson
  - Tape 35
    Side A: Charlotte Huck
    Side B: Charlotte Huck (cont'd); Les and Dorothy Moeller, The Limits to Growth; Ralph Reeder; Earl Butz; Man at Nrao (astronomer)
  - Tape 36
    Side A: Pastor's Wife, Sue Stacy; Forever Amber; A Farewell to Arms; Dick Stoufer; The New Science Politics; Norman Cousins; Virginia Mathews
    Side B: Virginia Mathews; Bookmobile; Bruce Oliver; Norman Cousins
  - Tape 37
    Side A: Professor Stan Idzerda; Julie James; Elnora Betsy Ross (Ray of Hope); Tom McCall
    Side B: Tom McCall (cont'd); Jim Green; Jane Anderson Gunn; Pat Walker (bar owner)
  - Tape 38
    Librarian (cont'd); Russ Wiggins; Lady Bible; John Hancock, Nuremburg Testimonies; Joe Howland (The Tru Believer); Manager (Education Our Daughter)
  - Tape 39
    Side A: Sue Stacy; Edwin Busick; Kathy Coster
    Side B: Kathy Coster (cont'd); Sue Stacy
  - Tape 40
    Side A: Interview (no name given); Nancy Larrick on reading; Irish Tom Campbell
    Side B: Sabines (miscellaneous)
  - Tape 41
    Side A: Person in State Department of Commerce, Hawaii; Mr. Amburgey, Asst. Commissioner of Education in Colorado; Utah Bookmobiles; John Zangmeister; Book Service to Alaskans
    Side B: Book Service to Alaskans (cont'd), Woman from Syria, Great Expectations
  - Tape 42
    Side A: Bess Sheller
    Side B: Silvia Barsuyan; Henry Dubinsky; Becky Pippert, Camping and Woodcraft; Head of Recreation, Richard A. Tapply; Man writing his memoirs; Eugene Power
  - Tape 43
    Side A: Cat's Cradle; Voltaire's Candide, Willard Thompson; Sue Stacy
    Side B: Firefighter, Clough; Augusta Baker; Dr. Kein; Melton; Sue Stacy; Marie Davis
  - Tape 44
    Side A: Pat Walker; Dorothy Moeller
    Side B: Art Smith, Shakespeare; Postman, Our Plundered Planet; Dan Lacy; Why people don't read (Nault); Susan Stamberg
  - Tape 45
    Side A: The Scottish Chiefs, The White Company, The Belgian Twings); Henry Taylor; Book about Clarence Darrow; Aristotle's Poetics; Sol Gordon; Candle maker; The Deaf
    Side B: Jane Howard; Doris Saunders; Betty Elliott; Minister's Daughter
  - Tape 46
    Side A: Director of Energy Research Lab; Man in Washington who served on committee in State Department
    Side B: The Americanization of Edward Buck; Nevada State Librarian; Book service to "Cathouses"; The Adveturers (Shirley); Crime and Punishment; Alaska mail delivery; Elizabeth Yon; Sue Stacey; Marie Davis; chatter
  - Tape 47
    Side A: Woody Hayes; Ed Koopminers; Helen E. Lee; Reverend Mullins; Ed Koopminers; Bruce Dixon
    Side B: Bruce Dixon; Zygmont Choroszy; Tim Melton; Hazel Dicken-Garcia; Tex Potter
  - Tape 48
    Side A: Jimmy Carter's Pastor, The Book of Acts; Bruce Edwards; Mortimer Adler; R. T. Kingman; Sue Stacy
    Side B: Sue Stacy (cont'd); Nancy Lopez Melton; Bill Branch
  - Tape 49
    Side A: Catherine Gillie on reading
    Side B: Crawford Lincoln Sturbridge; Gerald Utley; Catherine Gillie; Milton Caniff; Betty Elliot
  - Tape 50
    Side A: George Wilson (Director of Interlochen); Reading Researcher
    Side B: Poet, (Red Fox); Former President of Union and Lumber Inspec- tor; Zygmont Choroszy, underground newspaper in Poland
  - Tape 51
    Side A: Englishman, Reading Without Nonsense; Washburn, Huckleberry Finn; Bessie Moore, Dictionary; Nichols; Paul Ouelette-Silver
    Side B: Jeff MacNelly; Timothy Johnson; W. Lyle Eberhardt; Ed Newman; Babbitt; History book (no contact with non-whites); Speaking about Ghandi and Nehru; William Asp; Raymond Kuhn
  - Tape 52
    Side A: Former bookmobile driver; Sue Stacy
    Side B: Sue Stacy
  - Tape 53
    Side A: Simon Michael Bessie, Harper & Row; Nathan Leblang, architect
    Side B: Zygmont Choroszy; Robert B. Downs
  - Tape 54
    Side A: M/chf. Ray Kuhn; Mac Bundy; Leon Somat; Rabbi Friehof; Don Lee Keith
    Side B: Piano player; Ruby Bridges; Jeff McNelly; Connie Kay; Tony Randall; Andy Rooney
  - Tape 55
    Side A: Andy Rooney; Barbara Bannon; Herb Simon; Zygmont Choroszy
    Side B: Irv Kupcinet; Studs Terkel; Bob Cromie; Barbara Moro
- Cassette Tapes 56-75. (Box 7)
  - Tape 56
    Side A: Lady from Publishing Co.; Rita Furst; Clay Herrick; McClennan; Tom Barensfeld with Board of Education, Andre Cristo; Virginia Matthews, Nancy Oakley
  - Tape 57
    Side A: Cohn
    Side B: Man who has passages in a book marked
  - Tape 58
    Backup for Reel Tape of BTMTD Interview excerpts
  - Tape 59
    Side A: Helen Hoke Watts
    Side B: Helen Hoke Watts
  - Tape 60
    WRNG in Atlanta - Ray Mooney interview show, August 2, 1980
  - Tape 61
    "4/6/81 BTMTD"
  - Tape 62
    Side A: Jonard
    Side B: Linda Letizia
  - Tape 63
    Side A: Linda Letizia (cont'd)
    Side B: Ragland
  - Tape 64
    Side A: Ross
    Side B: Fleharty (in Alaska)
  - Tape 65
    Side A: Hart
    Side B: Branch
  - Tape 66
    Side A: Blue Collar Journal
    Side B: Ann Garcia
  - Tape 67
    Side A: 60 Minutes Self-Examination
    Side B: 60 Minutes (cont'd); Coster
  - Tape 68
    Side A: Ross; Hart
    Side B: Dottie Lamm
  - Tape 69
    Radio Call-in Show with Jim Eason
  - Tape 70
    1/27/81 Gordon Sabine Interview - aired as Public Affairs Pro- gram on WVWR in Roanoke, VA on 2/18/81
  - Tape 71
    copy of Tape 70
  - Tape 72
    Gordon Sabine speech about BTMTD (for Center for the Book?), April, 1981
  - Tape 73
    "All Things Considered" interview—National Public Radio, 2/6/81. Gordon Sabine interviewed by Susan Stamberg.
  - Tape 74